&lt;i&gt;--Hello? This is Jackie speaking.
&lt;i&gt;--喂?这是Jackie。
Hi my name is Tony and
this is Every Frame a Painting.
大家好。我叫Tony，这是Every Frame a Painting.
Some filmmakers can do action.
Others can do comedy
有的制片人会拍动作片。
有的会拍喜剧。
But for 40 years, the master of
combining them has been Jackie Chan.
在这40年，能把这些揉合在一起的大师就只有成龙。
These days, there's a lot of movies
that combine funny scenes
现在有好多电影既有滑稽的场景
with fight scenes.
But even when the movie’s good
和打斗场景。
可是即使电影好看
the comedy and action seem to be
two directors and two different styles.
喜剧和动作像是两个不同的导演和两个不一样的风格。
And that’s why Jackie’s so interesting.
所以成龙才显的那么有趣。
In his style, action IS comedy.
他的风格，动作片同时就是喜剧片。
And his work shows that the same
filmmaking principles apply
whether you’re trying to be funny
or kick ass.
在他的电影中都是同一种原则运用在滑稽或者踢屁股。
So let’s dive in. If you’d like to
see the names of the films
我们开始吧。（如果你想知道这些电影的名字
as I’m talking,
press the CC button below.
点击下面的cc按钮) [这是从原来YouTube上录的）。
Ready? Let’s go.
准备好了吗？开始。
So how does Jackie create
action that is also funny?
那成龙是怎么做到的呢？
First off, he gives himself
a disadvantage.
首先，他让自己处于被动。
No matter what film, Jackie always
starts beneath his opponents.
他的每部片，成龙处于对手的下风。
He has no shoes. He’s handcuffed.
他没鞋子。他手被铐。
He has a bomb in his mouth.
他嘴含炸弹。
From this point, he has to
fight his way back to the top.
从这起，他要打到最后。
Each action creates
a logical reaction.
每个动作都要有个合乎逻辑的反应。
And by following the logic...
然后跟着这个主线。。。
we get a joke.
来个笑话。
In movies, this comedic style
goes back to the silent clowns
这个风格追溯到默剧里的小丑。
like Chaplin, Lloyd, and Kea
ton.
卓别林，勞埃德， 基頓
But I think Jackie has distilled it
down to one line of dialogue:
可是我觉得成龙把它浓缩成一句台词。
&lt;i&gt;--Please! I said I don't want trouble!
我真不想找麻烦！
Because he’s the underdog,
Jackie has to get creative
因为他处于下风，他必须急中生智。
which brings us to point number two:
he uses anything around him.
这就来到第二阶段：
他必须利用所有可以利用到的道具。
This is the most famous
aspect of his style.
这就是他风格中最有名的那部分。
take something familiar,
do something unfamiliar.
用一些常见的东西，
做成不寻常的效果。
I’ve seen him fight with chairs
常见的用椅子打斗
dresses
裙子
chopsticks
筷子
keyboards
键盘
Legos
乐高
refrigerators
冰箱
and of course:
当然（梯子。。。）
Not only does this make
each fight organic and grounded
这些生活中常见的道具不仅让打斗变得有生命力更接地气
it also gives us jokes that
couldn’t happen anywhere else.
而且让观众忍俊不禁，这样场景生活中是看不到的。
Number 3: Jackie likes clarity.
第三，成龙的场景总是很清晰。
He doesn’t do dark scenes where
everything is color corrected blue.
他从来不拍那一种校正蓝色处理的黑暗场景。
If his opponent wears black,
he wears white.
如果他的对手穿黑色,他穿白
And if his opponent’s in white,
then he’s stylin'
如果他的对手穿白，他就花里胡哨
His framing's so clear that in each shot
he’s setting up the next bit of action.
他的构思清晰。他在每个画面都含有下一个画面的因素。
Here, even though we’re
watching the stuntman,
这里，虽然我们在看替身
two-thirds of frame is the staircase.
A few seconds later, we see why
这画面三分之二是后面的楼梯。
很快我们就发现为什么。
He keeps things clear by rarely
using handheld or dolly moves.
他极少运用人工或手推车，就为了让画面清晰。
&lt;i&gt;--Like American movies, there’s a lotta
movement. When the camera angle moves
&lt;i&gt;--在美国电影，所有东西都在动。如果摄影机在动
&lt;i&gt;--that means the actors,
they don’t know how to fight.
&lt;i&gt;-- 你就知道演员并不真打。
In slow-motion you can see how the
camera operator swings around
在慢动作，我们注意到摄影机的快速移动
to make the hits seem more violent.
让不专业的打斗显的暴力。
But since Jackie CAN fight...
可是成龙会打。。。
&lt;i&gt;--I never move my camera.
Always steady. Wide-angle.
&lt;i&gt;-- 我永远不动我的摄像机。让它保持稳定。拍广角。
&lt;i&gt;--Let him see I jumping down,
I do the flip, I do the fall
&lt;i&gt;-- 让观众看我跳下来，翻跟斗，摔倒。
When you shoot this way, everything
looks more impressive because
如果你用这个方法，所有东西更精彩因为
action and reaction are
in the same frame.
动作跟结果在同一画面。
Notice how you can always see Jackie,
the car and the wall at the same time.
注意看成龙，追车，和后面的墙一直在画面里.
But a similar stunt from Rush Hour 3
他在火拼時速3拍了同样的情节
never includes all the elements in the
same shot, and it doesn’t work.
可是这次他没把所有的元素人，车，墙等等放在同一画面，所以效果不好。
The same principle applies to comedy.
这个方法也能应用在喜剧。
This shot, directed by Sammo Hung,
shows us
在这个洪金宝拍的场景
the punch, the bad guy’s face
and Jackie’s face all in one.
拳头，坏人的头，和成龙的头都在画面里。
Now check out the same gag
in Shanghai Noon.
看同个玩笑在西域威龍。
Here, action and reaction
are separate shots.
在这里，动作，结果被分开了。
It kinda works, but not nearly as well.
效果很接近，但不够好。
Why don’t more directors do this?
为什么没有更多的导演这样做？
Because of number 5:
they don’t have enough time.
因为第5:没时间。
Jackie is perfectionist willing to do as
many takes as necessary to get it right
成龙是个完美主义者：愿意一直做到对。
And in Hong Kong,
he’s supported by the studio
而且香港的电影制片厂很支持他
which gives him
months to shoot a fight.
所以他能为了拍一个打斗场景花好几个月。
&lt;i&gt;--And the most difficult thing is
when I throw the fan and it comes back.
最难的是我把扇子扔出去，然后它自己飞回来。
&lt;i&gt;More than 120 takes. Those kind of
scenes, you say "Oh, Jackie's good."
拍了120 次才可能成功一次这种特技你看了，说“成龙厉害”
&lt;i&gt;It's not good. You can do it. Except
do you have the patience or not?
其实一点不厉害。你可以做得到。就看你有没有这样耐心。
When I rewatch his work,
these little things
在他电影这小事情
are the ones
I’m most impressed by.
反而是我印象最深刻的。
He doesn’t need to do them,
and they eat into his budget.
他真的不需要拍，而且很花钱
But he still does them
because he wants to.
可是他还愿意拍，因为他就要这么拍。
And it’s that “going above and beyond”
that I respect and admire.
这种精益求精的精神是让我尊重和欣赏。
&lt;i&gt;--But in America,
they don’t allow you to do that.
可是在美国你不能这样子做
&lt;i&gt;You know, because money.
因为太花钱。
And his American work is
missing something else:
而且他的美国电影还差一些别的：
&lt;i&gt;--And there’s a rhythm also,
to the way that the shots are performed
他表演和剪辑的节奏。
&lt;i&gt;and also the way they’re edited, and
Jackie said something very interesting
成龙说的很有意思：
&lt;i&gt;that the audience don’t know the
rhythm’s there until it’s NOT there.
？？？
Jackie’s fight scenes have
a distinct musical rhythm,
成龙的打斗场景总有一种特别的音乐节奏，
a timing he works out
on set with the performers.
他跟表演者准备好的时机。
&lt;i&gt;--Ready, action.
Stay where you are!
摄像，开拍. 别动
&lt;i&gt;Stay where you are,
don't chase me.
别动。别追。
&lt;i&gt;See? Everybody looks good.
大家都好看。
Even experienced martial artists
have trouble with it.
即使有经验的武打演员也很难掌握。
In his earliest films, you see him
learning the timing from Yuan Heping
在他最早的电影他从袁和平学到了这种节奏
and it’s very much like Chinese opera.
有点像戏曲。
But by the mid-1980s,
working with his own stunt team
可是到80年代，他有自己的动作团队
He had something totally unique.
才创造了一个很新很特别的风格。
In America, many directors and
editors don’t understand this timing.
美国的导演，剪輯者不重视这种节奏。
And they ruin it by
cutting on every single hit.
他们把连贯的动作剪的七零八碎。
Bu  in Hong Kong, directors
hold their shots long enough
可是香港导演尽量保持画面完整
for the audience to feel the rhythm.
让观众感觉到节奏。
&lt;i&gt;--The most important part
is the editing.
最重要的部分是剪輯.
&lt;i&gt;Most directors,
they don’t know how to edit.
绝大部分的导演不懂剪輯。
&lt;i&gt;Even the stunt coordinators,
they don’t know how to edit.
连武術指導都不懂剪輯。
Hong Kong directors like Jackie
and Sammo cut a particular way.
香港的导演（成龙， 洪金寶)有种特别的剪輯风格
In the first shot, you hit
your opponent in the wide.
在第一个画面，你在广角打你的对手。
In the second shot,
you get a nice close-up.
第二个画面，有个特写。
But when you cut the shots together,
you DON'T match continuity.
可是连接的时候，不要保持连续性
At the end of shot 1, the elbow is here.
第一个镜头结尾，他的手肘在这里。
At the beginning of shot 2,
it's all the way back here.
可是在第二个镜头开头，还是从前面开始。
These 3 frames are for the audience’s
eyes to register the new shot.
前面三个画面是为了最后有力的动作做铺垫。
And they make all the difference.
这样子才精彩。
&lt;i&gt;--I start from here, then here,
But two shots, combined
从这，这。两者结合
&lt;i&gt;That's power.
这才有冲击力。
In other words, show it TWICE
and the audience's mind will make it
换句话，关键的动作让他们看两次
one hit that’s stronger.
这一拳才有力。
By contrast, modern American editing
doesn't show the hit at all.
与此相反，现代美国式剪辑就根本不表现这一拳
At the end of shot 1, the leg is here.
在第一组镜头结尾，腿脚在这里。
At the beginning of shot 2, it’s in
the same place, going backwards.
在第二组镜头，腿脚在同样的点，已经弹回来了。
But because they cut at
the exact frame of the hit
可是因为剪辑师把击倒的那刻剪掉
it doesn’t feel like a hit.
这就不像真正的打击。
A lot of people think this is
because of the PG-13 rating
很多人以为这是因为电影分级
but even R-rated films do this now
可是限制级的电影也是这样。
It looks like a bunch of
people flailing around
看的像一群人手舞足蹈
instead of a bunch of
people getting hurt.
而不是一群人挨揍了
Ouch.
Which brings us to number 8: pain.
到了第8点了：痛。
Unlike a lot of action stars,
who try to look invincible
不像其他不可战胜的功夫明星，
Jackie gets hurt.
成龙也会挨揍。
A lot.
还不少。
Half the fun of his work is that
not only are the stunts impressive
他的电影好看不只是精彩特技
There’s always room for a joke.
总是可以搞笑。
Pain humanizes him.
Because
no matter how skilled he is
不管他多厉害他还会挨揍。
He still gets smacked in the face.
挨揍也会痛。
In fact, Jackie’s face may
actually be his greatest asset
成龙的脸就是他最大的优势。
Many times the look he gives
is all it takes to sell a joke.
很多时候他的脸就是笑点
Like when he does an entire fight
holding a chicken.
比方说整场打戏他手上拎着一只鸡。
Or dressed as Chun-li
或者打扮像春丽。
And last, Jackie’s style always ends
with a real payoff for the audience.
最后，他的风格让观众觉得看的过瘾。
By fighting his way from the bottom, he
earns the right to a spectacular finish.
从底层打起一路打到辉煌的结局。
He doesnt win cause hes a better fighter
He wins because he doesn’t give up
他赢不是比别人好。而是从不言弃。
This relentlessness makes his finales
really impressive and really funny
这样博命演出才有精彩而有趣的结局。
And it’s in direct contrast to
a lot of his American work
跟美国的作品有强烈对比
where bad guys are defeated
because someone shoots them
美国电影里，坏人被打败是因为他们挨枪子。
COME ON.
又来了。总是这套。
But most of all, I think
Jackie’s style proves something:
最重要的：成龙的风格证明
action and comedy aren’t that different.
武打跟喜剧没有那么大区别。
In both genres, we want
to see our best performers
不管哪种类，我们只要看最好的表演者
And I think a lot of modern
action directors are failing completely.
在这方面我觉得现在的动作片导演完全失败了。
These actors are skilled artists,
some of the best in the world.
我们有很多一流的艺术家。
Why are the directors so unskilled?
为什么导演那么不专业？
Why am I paying money
to NOT see the action?
我花了钱，为什么没看到好的动作片？
&lt;i&gt;--Whatever you do, do the best you can
because the film lives forever.
你应该倾全力做到最好
因为这部电影永远都在。
&lt;i&gt;"No, because that day it was raining
and the actor don't have time."
“我们不能，因为那一天下了雨，演员没时间”。
&lt;i&gt;I said, would you go to every theater
to tell the audience? No.
我问：你能去每个电影院给观众们解释吗？不能。
&lt;i&gt;The audience sits in the theater:
good movie, bad movie that’s all
观众坐在电影院：好看，不好看。那么简单。
Exactly. This work will last.
对。这部电影永远就是这样子。
And on that note,
I leave you with
我说到这里，给你看
the greatest death scene
in film history.
历史上最精彩的死亡的场景。